<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</title>
    <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanpeng.github.io/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Writing Sample: Build a Static Site with Hugo on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_hugo_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_hugo_github/</guid>
      <description>A Writing Sample: Build a Static Site with Hugo on GitHub
(https://susanpeng.github.io/post/hugo-how-to/)
I wrote this how-to to record the steps I used to create a static website using Hugo and got it running on GitHub.
To set up the static site, I watched several YouTube videos and checked several articles on Google.
These steps are proven correct so that I can follow them for my following static website setup. That would save me a lot of time searching for information or reading the Hugo manual from the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience with Git and Docs-as-code</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/experience_with_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/experience_with_git/</guid>
      <description>Git I’ve about three years of experience using Git and its command line. With ten+ years of experience using Unix and Linux shell scripts, I don’t have any problem using Git and its command-line. In contrast, they allow me to work more efficiently. I use Git to store my projects, host my websites, and collaborate with others.
Docs as code Docs as Code refers to the concept that technical writers write docs with the same tool-chain as developers, using issue trackers, version control, plain text markup, code review, and automated tests, integrating the documentation process with the development workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with GitHub</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/git-how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/git-how-to/</guid>
      <description>Install git on the local computer
Check if git has already been installed on my Mac:
1 2  git --version git version 2.30.1 (Apple Git-130)   I got &amp;ldquo;git version 2.30.1 (Apple Git-130)&amp;quot;; that means I have already got git installed on my Mac.
If you can see the version information, you need to download and install git on your computer.
Create a free GitHub account
Go to GitHub website and sign up to get a free GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
