<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samples on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</title>
    <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/categories/samples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Samples on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanpeng.github.io/categories/samples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Complete a Project</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/complete_a_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/complete_a_project/</guid>
      <description>“Yes! I did it.” You&amp;rsquo;ve completed your ice breaker and got the written evaluation from your evaluator besides the oral evaluation at the meeting.
But when you log into your Toastmasters International account and go to your Pathway curriculum, you can’t see the checkmark on the right top corner of your project. It doesn’t show the completion of the project. What should you do? Ask your evaluator or your VP of Education?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-source Publishing</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/singlesource_sum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/singlesource_sum/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, there are many different kinds of media formats such as a PDF file for reading on a computer, an HTML searchable file for reading online, and an InDesign file for paper printout publishing. In a traditional document management system, source files usually are authored in different formats for different publishing media. When a product is updated, the documentation that describes the product needs to be modified or even rewritten. A content maintenance team needs to apply changes on the same content to various versions of source files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Samples</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/video_samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/video_samples/</guid>
      <description>Getting Data From Amazon and Writing Them Into an Excel File (https://youtu.be/dOFGlra9-Lo)
Biljit&amp;rsquo;s Meditation Journal (https://youtu.be/Uru-vKoRt4A)
Kathyn&amp;rsquo;s Meditation Journal (https://youtu.be/kEgsS2QtdxY)
Ken&amp;rsquo;s Meditation Journal (https://youtu.be/r7E6k43JYZY)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writing Sample: Build a Static Site with Hugo on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_hugo_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_hugo_github/</guid>
      <description>A Writing Sample: Build a Static Site with Hugo on GitHub
(https://susanpeng.github.io/post/hugo-how-to/)
I wrote this how-to to record the steps I used to create a static website using Hugo and got it running on GitHub.
To set up the static site, I watched several YouTube videos and checked several articles on Google.
These steps are proven correct so that I can follow them for my following static website setup. That would save me a lot of time searching for information or reading the Hugo manual from the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Samples v20220131</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/writingsamples_v20220131/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/writingsamples_v20220131/</guid>
      <description>Build a Static Website with Hugo on GitHub (https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_hugo_github/)
Aegisub (https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_aegisub_explanation)
User&amp;rsquo;s Manual (https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_usersmanual_explanation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writing Sample: Installation Instructions</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_web_service_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_web_service_install/</guid>
      <description>Installation Instructions for a Web Service Application
(https://susanpeng.github.io/docs/pdf/ws_installation.pdf)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writing Sample: A RESTful API Document</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_restfulapi_explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_restfulapi_explanation/</guid>
      <description>A RESTful API documentat (https://morning90.herokuapp.com/)
I just moved this documention to a new site, so I will need to change some parameters in the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Writing Sample: Aegisub Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_aegisub_explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_aegisub_explanation/</guid>
      <description>Aegisub Quick Start (https://aegisubquickstart.wordpress.com/)
As an excellent subtitle-adding software, Aegisub has been used intensively in my company&amp;rsquo;s video production team. However, its official tutorial is highly text-intensive with little graphics, so training new team members took lots of time and effort.
My task was to create a Quick Start manual to help beginners start quickly and save time and effort for training.
I started by reading the original online manual; it was difficult to understand (perhaps they didn&amp;rsquo;t have a sufficient budget for documentation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Samples: User&#39;s Manual and Usability Testing Report</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_usersmanual_explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/ws_usersmanual_explanation/</guid>
      <description>Bookshelf Editor User&amp;rsquo;s Manual (https://susanpeng.github.io/docs/helpmanual/index.html)
Usability Testing Report (https://susanpeng.github.io/docs/helpmanualusa/index.html)
I created this User&amp;rsquo;s Mnual as my technical writing course project. I received the Bookshelf Editor program without any documentation. I had to go through the whole program to figure out all functions and operational steps by clicking menu items, buttons and links on the screen. After obtaining a sufficient understanding of the program, I created this User&amp;rsquo;s Manual. It was a great process of learning technical concepts and skills and then converting them into clear and concise content for a general audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Samples v20211225</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/writingsamples_v20211225/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/writingsamples_v20211225/</guid>
      <description>This document includes two projects:
  Aegisub Quick Start (https://aegisubquickstart.wordpress.com/)
As an excellent subtitle-adding software, Aegisub has been used intensively in my company&amp;rsquo;s video production team. However, its official tutorial is highly text-intensive with little graphics, so I wrote this Quick Start manual to help beginners start quickly and save time and effort during training. This Quick Start manual has significantly reduced the time and human power when training new team members and also dramatically reduced the learning curve for learners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
