<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</title>
    <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on Even - A super concise theme for Hugoaaa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://susanpeng.github.io/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Did I Become a Techncial Writer</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/become_writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/become_writer/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a technical writer, but I worked as a system analyst and developer for more than ten years before starting my technical writing career.
Do you want to know why and how a system analyst became a technical writer?
Here is how.
I got my first job as a system analyst and developer two months after landing in Toronto, Canada. I moved to Vancouver ten years later because it was too cold in Toronto, and Vancouver is much warmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Static Site with Hugo on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/hugo-how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/hugo-how-to/</guid>
      <description>I set up my first Hugo-generated website on GitHub through the following steps. I wrote this file to help whose familiar with GitHub and command line and want to build their static website using Hugo by following simple command lines without detailed explanations.
I&amp;rsquo;m using a Mac mini m1.
Instll Hugo
If you have Homebrew installed on your Mac, just run:
1  brew install hugo   The Hugo will be installed on the Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with GitHub</title>
      <link>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/git-how-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://susanpeng.github.io/post/git-how-to/</guid>
      <description>Install git on the local computer
Check if git has already been installed on my Mac:
1 2  git --version git version 2.30.1 (Apple Git-130)   I got &amp;ldquo;git version 2.30.1 (Apple Git-130)&amp;quot;; that means I have already got git installed on my Mac.
If you can see the version information, you need to download and install git on your computer.
Create a free GitHub account
Go to GitHub website and sign up to get a free GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
